《越狱》前情提要K
Previously on Prison Break:
有一个可信度高的证人刚出面 而且他愿意作证
A very credible witness has just come forward and he's willing to testify.
你所说的阴谋 他全都可以证实
He'll corroborate everything you've said about this conspiracy.
是谁？
Who?
你对索拿了解多少 金先生？
How much do you know about sona, Mr. Kim?
只了解上级透露给我的资讯 现在策略有些改变
Only what I've been given clearance on. There's been a change in strategy.
-我还要再走多远？ -这次你只需要去巴拿马
- How much further would I have to go? - For this, you only have to go to Panama.
-我不知道你会来 -你传讯说茶包在这
- I didn't know you were gonna be here. - You e-mailed me. You said T-Bag was here.
-你在网站上留言 -我没在网站上留言
- It's on the website. - I didn't write on no website.
-这件事越看越像陷阱 -他把犸丽囚禁起来
- This is looking more and more like a setup. - He's got Maricruz locked away.
我一定得帮他拿到钱 不然她就得等死
Either I help him get the money or she's dead.
站住，包威
Freeze, Bagwell!
西奥多包威 里面那个死女人是他杀的
Theodore Bagwell. He's the one you want for that dead chick in there.
-苏克，你最好振作点 -天啊
- Sucre, you better pull it together. - Oh, God!
去把钱抢回来，拜托
Go get the money. Please.
你在骗谁啊？
Who you fooling?
你不可能杀我的，白面书生
You ain't gonna kill me, Mr. Michelangelo.
你没那种胆量
You ain't got it in you.
-林克？ -你好，迈克
- Linc? - Hello, Michael.
你想干嘛，亚历？
What do you want, Alex?
把钱和船都交给我
Bring me the money. Bring me the boat.
你疯了
You are out of your mind.
我们手上都有 对方需要的东西
We have something the other person needs.
你的计划换你哥一命
Your brother for your plan,
我只给你五分钟考虑
Five minutes. That's what you have.
我没有杀人
I didn't kill that man,
我要把你救出去
I'm getting you out of here,
-我只剩下三周的时间 -对我有信心一点
- I got three weeks, - Just have a little faith,
我已经尽力了
I did everything I could,
我知道
I know you did,
先生
senor.
-要口香糖吗？ -不要
- Chicle? - No.
汽水？ 那啤酒呢，朋友？
Soda? Beer, my friend.
大麻烟？魔菇
Spleef? Magic mushrooms.
保证让你爽翻天
Burst your brain, split it wide open.
找我就对了，朋友
I'm your man, man.
奇幻之旅都在这箱子里
Magic Mystery Tour, right here in this box.
这里没有的话 我可以帮你弄到
If I don't got it, I can get it.
滚开
Beat it.
打算做对的事吗？
So you gonna do the right thing?
对谁是对的事，亚历？
Right for who, Alex?
你输了，迈克
You've lost, Michael,
都是你一手造成的
That's what you've done here.
你会失去更多 除非你此时此刻告诉我
You're gonna lose a whole lot more unless you tell me right here and right now...
你要把钱和船交给我
...you're gonna bring me the money, you're gonna bring me the boat.
然后你就会放我哥走
And you'll just let my brother go.
对
Yeah.
就像你让中间人 亚布兹和疯仔走一样
Just like you let Tweener go and Abruzzi and Haywire.
现在情况不同了
Things are different now.
-真的？ -对
- Really? - Yeah,
我以前效命的人 他们K算是把我卖到下游
The people I was working for, they kind of sold me down the river.
现在我只想出海
Now, I just wanna go out to sea.
真好笑 这笑话我要记起来
That's funny. I'll have to remember that one.
我面临的刑期比你还长
I face more prison time than you.
我在全民公敌名单上的 名次忽然领先了你
Sort of jumped ahead of you a few spots on the public enemy list.
迈克，你我是彼此 得到自由的救星
You're my way to freedom, Michael, and I'm yours.
我们都清楚对方的能耐
We both know what the other one's capable of,
不如互相尊重 不耍花招、技俩
Let's treat each other with respect here, No games, no bluffing,
当作是两条汉子互相帮忙
Just two guys doing each other a favor.
你意下如何？
What do you say?
你在哪里？
Where are you?
米拉佛瑞斯码头 在巴拿马市郊
Mira Flores shipping docks, just outside of Panama City.
是河边的一间大仓库
It's a big warehouse right on the water.
那可是路途遥远
That's a long ways.
我至少要24小时才能到
It'll take me at least 24 hours to get there.
那就快出发吧
Well, then, I'd get moving.
逃亡的感觉如何？
How's it feel being on the run?
-我死不了的 -被逮到你就死定了
- I'll survive. - Not if they catch you.
你会被送上电椅
They'll send you to the chair.
你觉得很讽刺吗？
You think that's ironic?
那是伸张正义
It'd be justice.
金先生，我是亚历曼宏
Mr. Kim. Alex Mahone.
打电话给我
Call me.
正义一定会被伸张的
Oh, justice will be served.
我即将透露的讯息 极有可能让我丧命
What I'm about to divulge to you will in all likelihood get me killed.
-事实上，我保证活不了 -那么你为何要出面？
- Actually, I guarantee it. - Then why are you doing it?
因为这件事本来应该是 为了国家、忠诚
Because this was supposed to be about country, about loyalty...
以及做正确的事 但其实不然
...about what's right, but it wasn't.
因为我冤枉了 不该被冤枉的人
Because I wronged people who should not have been wronged.
这些命令都是由 卡洛琳雷诺兹下达
Those orders were given by Caroline Reynolds...
她当时是副总统
...who was vice president at the time.
接获命令后，我栽赃证据
Acting on those orders, I planted evidence.
我取得一具尸体 当晚我用另一场暗杀为由
I procured a body, I lured Lincoln Burrows into that parking garage that evening...
引诱林克柏劳到停车场
...under the auspices of a different hit.
我们从零开始陷害他
From the ground up, we framed him.
好极了
Perfect.
林克柏劳被处决 民众就会忘记戴伦斯史泰门
See, Lincoln Burrows gets executed, people forget about Terrence steadman...
还有环绕他与总统的争议
...the controversy surrounding him and the presidency.
而大众不会知道“公司”的事
And nobody ever knows about the Company.
对，那是个神秘的 阴谋集团
Yes, which is a shadowy cabal of corporations...
对全国大大小小的一切 都有影响力
...that pretty much influence everything that happens in this country.
但我看不出这件事 和莎拉丹奎迪有何关联
But I fail to see how any of this is relevant to sara Tancredi...
以及她协助逃犯 和弃保潜逃的事实
...and the fact that she aided and abetted, that she jumped bail.
她这么做是因为生命受到威胁 这合情合理
She did so because she feared for her life, which was appropriate...
因为我授命要杀了她
...as I had orders to kill her.
等等
Hey.
魔术生意还营业吗？
You still in the magic business?
-你叫什么名字？ -查可
- What's your name? - Chaco.
证据都在这
It's all here,
凯勒曼先生所说的一切 这些文件都可证明
Everything Mr. Kellerman said is corroborated in these documents.
鉴于这些证据，我想请问
In light of this evidence, my question, I guess to you...
你是否该花时间和资源
...is whether your time and resources are best spent...
继续起诉丹奎迪医生？
...in pursuing charges against Dr. Tancredi.
不，检方会立刻 撤销所有控告
No. My office will drop all charges effective immediately.
但是庭上 我想将我方的时间与焦点
But, Your Honor, I would like to devote my time and attention...
转移到起诉这个人 凯勒曼先生
...in prosecuting this man, Mr. Kellerman.
法警
Officer.
我真的不知该说什么
I literally don't even know what to say to you.
我很高兴认识你，莎拉
It was good knowing you, sara.
-说 -情况如何？
- Yeah? - Where are we?
我在巴拿马，是个好地方
I'm in Panama, Nice place,
天气晴朗，微风凉爽
Good weather. Cool breeze.
那两兄弟的情况如何？
Where are we with the brothers?
等你抓到他们 我要亲自过去确认
When you get them, I wanna come down there for confirmation,
那我建议你上飞机了
I suggest you get on a plane,
因为等你抵达，斯科菲尔德 和柏劳就会在你要的地方
Because by the time you get here, I'll have scofield and Burrows where you want them.
整件事就结束了
And then this whole thing is over.
莎拉，是我
Sara, it's me.
这感觉好奇怪
It's a strange thing...
留了言，却知道 对方永远不能收到
...leaving a message for someone you know is never gonna get it.
我只能做最坏的打算
I can only assume the worst...
所以K这是我 最后一次给你的留言
...so this'll be the last message I'll leave for you.
我只想告诉你我到了
I just wanted you to know that I made it.
但少了你，我开心不起来
But it's no good without you.
总之，你记得我说K
Anyway, remember when I?
记得我说 在下加利福尼亚的酒吧
Remember when I told you about those 50-cent beers...
畅饮时段 啤酒一瓶只要五角吗？
...in Baja at happy hour?
这里的酒更便宜
Well, they're even cheaper down here.
如果奇迹发生 你听到留言的话
And if by some miracle you do get this...
请你仔细听好
...I need you to listen close.
莎拉
Sara.
莎拉，我们最好离开了
Sara, I suggest we get you out of here.
外面会有大批媒体包围 而且只会越来越多，走吧
It's gonna be a media circus outside and it'll only get bigger. Let's go.
好
Sure.
今日，在丹奎迪医生案的审理 出现了更为意想不到的结果
Larger unexpected fireworks at the trial of Dr, Sara Tancredi in chicago today,
新的证词暗示 前总统雷诺兹
New testimony has implicated that former President Reynolds,,,
同谋捏造 胞弟戴伦斯史泰门之死
,,, was complicit in the falsification of her brother Terrence Steadman's death,
而此案的余波是 据传的凶手
The fallout from all this, the purported killer,,,
之前被全国性通缉的 林克柏劳
,,, Lincoln Burrows, who has led the country on a nationwide manhunt,,,
针对他的所有控诉 现在将立即撤销
,,, will be exonerated of all charges effective immediately,
天啊，布鲁斯 林克自由了
oh, my God, Bruce. Lincoln's a free man.
片名：越狱风云
剧名：巴拿马生死斗
迈克留言给我，天啊K
Michael left me a message. Okay. My God.
他还不知道 他还在计划逃亡
He doesn't know. He's still planning on running.
迈克，快接电话
Come on, Michael. Come on, come on, come on.
我来做介绍
Let me do the intro.
好，之后由我说话
Fine. Then I'll do the talking.
好吧，我得去找他
Okay, I gotta go to him.
-他在三千里外 -没错
- What's that, about 3000 miles? - It is.
我们得先回饭店一趟 你再送我去机场
So we're gonna have to swing by my hotel, and you'll have to get me to the airport.
他一定要知道不用再逃了 他现在的行为会害死自己
He's gotta know he doesn't have to run. What he's doing is gonna get him killed.
情势终于对了，长官
The stars are finally aligning, sir.
曼宏抓到柏劳 斯科菲尔德马上就到
Mahone's got Burrows. Scofield's on his way.
（索拿？）
I will make it happen. I am going down there myself.
我会办妥 我正要亲自去一趟
（只需要一个人）
I assume we both know which one that is.
我想我们都清楚 这指的是哪一个人
我抵达时会通知你
I will call you when I get down there.
我K要你仔细听，好吗？
I just... I want you to listen really, really close, okay?
-亚历K慢慢说 -好K
- Alex, Alex, slow down, - okay, okay, fine.
我们谈过复合 再给彼此一次机会
We talked about getting back together, about giving it another shot.
对，我说也许可以试试
Yes, and I said that maybe we could.
-亚历？ -你觉得哥伦比亚如何？
- Alex? - What about Colombia?
-卡塔黑那？ -去那里？
- Cartagena? - Go there?
你快放暑假了，不是吗？
Well, you got summer break coming up, don't you?
-小卡也是吧？ -对，可是K
- Same with cam? - Yeah. But...
因为我现在离那里不远
Listen, I'm not far from there right now...
我想不如多留几天 你们也一起来找我如何？
...and I was thinking that why not just stick around and have you guys come down?
你不是一直很想去吗？
I mean, you always wanted to go, didn't you?
-造访你的故乡？ -对，可是你不想去
- Visit the homeland? - Yes, but you didn't.
对，可是我现在想去
Yeah, but I do now.
好，我应该可以去 可以在暑假结束前
Yeah. I mean, I suppose I could, we could maybe do two weeks...
去度假两周，或是K
,,, at the end of the summer, or...
-你答应了？是答应了吧？ -对K
- Is that a yes? That's a yes, right? - Yes, yes.
这里咖啡和海滩很棒 小卡可以去野生公园K
Great coffee, great beaches, wildlife parks for Cam and...
听我说，你要有行不通的 心理准备，好吗？
Look, it might not work out. You've gotta be prepared for that, okay? L...
我们之间 和以前不一样了
It can't be like it was before.
没办法和以前一样的
It will never be like before.
现在我知道什么比较重要
I know what's important now. I know what matters.
我可以去网路上查资料
Well, I guess I could look online,
我不知道，我该走了
I don't know, I should go,
来陪我吧，潘
Just come be with me, Pam.
和我在一起
Be with me,
（巴拿马市，巴拿马 圣马提亚斯医院）
不用担心，好吗？
Hey, you got nothing to worry about, okay?
我要嫁的人是你
It's you I'm marrying.
甘萨列先生
Senor Gonzales.
（你在做什么？）
（出院）
（太荒谬了 你有低血容积性休克）
（你流失三品脱的血液）
（那是身体血量的30%）
（会对肾脏和大脑造成伤害 甚至造成死亡）
（我要找美国大使馆）
（麻烦帮我接过去）
美国大使馆总机
U, S, Embassy operator,
我要找一个朋友 一个失踪的美国朋友
I'm looking for a friend. A missing American friend.
他可能在医院里 也可能在牢里
He could be in the hospital. He could be in jail.
姓名是？
Name?
贝里克，布拉德贝里克
Bellick. Brad Bellick.
过来K我到底能不能 打电话给律师？
Hey! Hey, do I get to call my lawyer or what?!
你们都是野人吗？
What are you, savages down here?
我有权利打电话给律师
I get to call my lawyer or something.
该死的香蕉农
Freaking banana benders.
终于来了，就是他
Finally! That's him!
他就是杀死那女孩的凶手
That's the guy. He's the one that killed that girl.
干得好，各位
Good job, guys.
等等，你们不放我出去？
Hey. Hey, aren't you gonna release me now?
等等
Hey.
Hey!
-你死定了 -是吗？
- You're busted. - Am I?
-钱在哪里？ -在帅哥手上
- Where's the money? - Pretty Boy's got it.
他在外消遥 你却在这蹲苦窑
He's out there with a royal flush, and you're in here with a busted straight.
-一点都不公平对吧？ -你也好不到哪里
- That hardly seems right, does it? - Your hand don't look much better.
也许我手上还有王牌
Maybe I got an ace up my sleeve.
你知道什么内情？
You know something I don't?
坐下歇脚吧，老大
You should rest your leg, boss.
（迪哈苏，你好吗？）
（查可，有事吗？）
（我带了个有钱人来找你）
（你搞什么鬼？）
（别紧张，我只想做生意） （滚下船）
听说我们可以交易
I was told we could make a deal.
你来错地方了，小子 这里没有你做得起的交易
You're a long ways from home, boy. There ain't no deal for you here.
你还没听到 我能提供的东西
You haven't heard what I have to offer.
长得像你这样的人来这里？
A guy looking like you do, coming here?
只会让我坐牢
Only thing you offering is jail time.
（你疯了吗？带警察来？）
我不是警察
I'm not a cop.
没关系
上网查查 输入迈克斯科菲尔德
Check online. Type in Michael scofield.
这名字对我毫无意义
That means nothing to me.
可能价值十万美金
Could mean a hundred grand.
你浪费我超过30秒 我就让你下水
This takes longer than 30 seconds, you're in the canal.
当成鲶鱼的饵
Bait for the catfish.
等等
Hey.
（他在这里）
（十万美金赏金，迈克斯科菲尔德）
你刚给了我 十万个理由举发你
You just gave me a hundred thousand reasons to turn you in.
的确
That's true.
看来我只好给你更多 好让你不举发我
I guess I'll just have to give you a few more not to.
你知道我是清白的
You know I'm innocent.
-对，大概是吧 -但你却不在乎
- Yeah, probably. - And yet you don't care.
除了找回我的人生 其他我一概不在乎
I don't care about anything other than getting my life back, no.
你妻子知道你的真面目吗？
Your wife know who you really are?
你应该很了解的
Hey, you know how it is.
因为情势所逼 好人只好做坏事
Good men doing bad things because of circumstance.
如果我是你，我会再打给她 叫她永远忘记你这个人
I'd call her back if I were you. Tell her to forget you were ever born.
你会这么做是吗？
Oh, you would, would you?
让你人生的癌症 别扩散到他们的人生
Stop the cancer from your life spreading to theirs.
我人生的癌症？
Cancer of my life?
要不是你和你的烂人生 我也不会
I wouldn't be begging her to meet me in this third world dump...
求她来这落后的烂国家
...if it weren't for you and your life.
你已经没有出路了 我们都是如此
There's no way out of this for you. For any of us.
对我而言有出路
For me, there is.
我还有出路
-你花掉多少钱？ -十到二十万
- How much of it you spend? - A hundred thousand. Two.
当然了 在这里用起来像是一百万
Of course, down here, be more like a million.
感觉就像路易14世
Be Louis XIV for a sum like that.
巴拿马太阳王
The sun King of Panama.
我看以后你要见到太阳 不太容易
You ain't gonna be seeing much sun now.
我可不确定喔
I don't know.
你知道吗，包威？ 在这八人之中
You know, Bagwell, out of all the guys, all eight of them...
我最希望和你 来场激烈的枪战
...you were the guy I was hoping would go down in a blaze of gunfire.
不如拿出你的真本事 把我解决掉吧
Why don't you give me your best shot? Finish the job.
也许我会这么做
Maybe I will.
你那逞罗猫的贼笑 让我更想把你给轰掉
That siamese cat smile just makes me wanna open you up that much more.
笑脸猫 是笑脸猫的微笑
It's Cheshire. Cheshire cat smile.
我可以走了？
I'm free?
等等
Hey.
这是怎么回事？
Hey, what the hell is this?
等等K那他呢？
Hey, wait, wait a minute. What about him?
他才是凶手
He's the one that did it.
什么意思？ 你刚刚说什么？
What's that mean? Buena suerte? What does that mean?
祝你好运
Good luck.
（雷罗卡达警局 往这边走吗？）
（对）
（你需要帮忙吗？）
贝里克
Bellick.
Bellick!
我的犸丽在哪里？
Where is mi Maricruz?
她在哪里？
Where is she?
救我出去
想知道她在哪里 就想法子救我出去
You wanna know where she is, find a way to get me out of this!
救我出去
Get me out of here!
苏克，救我出去
Sucre, get me out of this! Get me out!
犸丽
Maricruz.
犸丽K
（巴拿马市 米拉佛瑞斯码头）
迈克，那艘船真美
Michael, that's a beautiful boat.
答应我拿去之后把船名改了
Just promise you'll change the name when you take it.
我想我母亲 不会喜欢你这个人
I don't think my mother would have approved of you.
没问题，过来
Consider it done. Come on.
-把手铐解开 -还不行
- Uncuff me. - No, not yet.
现在你要反悔了吗？
So is this the part where you go back on your word?
手举起来K
Hands up, hands up.
不
No.
现在他们要留你活口
As of now, they want you alive.
为什么？
Why?
好问题
That's a good question.
你以后自己去想解答 钱在哪里？
Figure it out some day, on your own time. Where's the money?
-放开他 -不行
- Cut him loose. - No.
拜托，亚历 船已经是你的了
Come on, Alex. You already got the boat.
-对我有点信心 -钱
- Show a little good faith. - The money.
我要K
I want...
-说 -我到了，你在哪？
- Yeah? - I'm here, Where are you?
仓库里面
I'm inside the warehouse.
我马上到
I'll be right there.
好戏上场
Here we go.
-喂？ -喂
- Hello? - Hello.
-你会说英文吗？ -会，我能效劳吗？
- You speak English? - Yes, sir, can I help you?
-是，在米拉佛瑞斯码头 -一切都还好吗？
- Yes, yes. Mira Flores docks. - Everything all right?
-这里发生谋杀案 -你有危险吗？
- Yes. There's been a murder. - Are you in danger?
有两个美国人 射杀一名穿西装的亚洲男子
A well-dressed Asian man has just been shot by two Americans.
-我们立刻派车去 -好，快来
- We'll send a car right away, - Come. Yes, come.
你要杀了他，栽赃给我们
So you kill him and frame us.
为什么？
Why?
这样大家 就不会来找我麻烦
So everyone will leave me alone.
因为我只想要这样 还有那笔钱
Because that's all I want. That, and the money.
-不可能，亚历，放开他 -把钱给我
- It's not gonna happen, Alex. Let him go. - Give me the money.
-放开他 -把钱给我
- Let him go. - Give me the money!
真是不敢置信
I am dumbfounded.
别客气，他们是你的了
Well, don't be shy. They're all yours.
你说他们会在我要的地方
You said you'd have them right where we wanted them.
这里不是我要的地方
This isn't right where we want them.
那是你的工作了
Well, that's your job now.
我的职责结束了
This is as far as I go.
或是你另有目的？
Or is it something else?
我们都聚在这里 有其他理由吗？
Another reason we're all here?
例如这理由
Like that.
-例如黑吃黑 -正是如此，说再见吧
- Like a double-cross. - Yeah, just like that. Say goodbye.
英雄所见略同 可不是吗，亚历？
Great minds think alike, eh, Alex?
快点K
Okay, come on, come on.
坐下后，四肢的手铐 会固定在车地板上
Once seated, your four-piece will be mounted to the floor-mount.
移送过程中不得与我交谈
During transport, do not speak to either I, myself...
我懂规定
I know the drill.
进去
Get in.
-多久要到？30分钟内？ -对，差不多
- So, what have we got, 30 minutes? - Yeah, something like that.
-你干嘛不走高速公路？ -尖峰时段
- Why didn't you take the freeway? - Rush hour.
-该死 -怎么了？
- Oh, hell. - What?
-引擎故障灯亮了 -调配场才刚检查过这台车
- The engine light just came on. - It just got serviced at motor pool.
对，但我们得停车确认一下
Yeah. We've gotta pull over just to make sure.
我去检查
All right, I'll check it out.
在法国反抗组织中 面对纳粹行刑队是种光荣
In the French Resistance, it was a high honor to face a Nazi firing squad.
-我不是叫你闭嘴吗？ -代表你很厉害
- Thought I told you to be quiet. - Meant you did your job.
当他们射死你时 面带微笑更是荣誉
The highest honor was to smile when they shot you.
你们早该来了
Took you long enough.
从加通湖到东运河
Lake Gatun. Eastern canal.
（巴拿马运河，加通湖）
Approaches to Cartegena. Twenty-seven-fifty.
再到卡塔黑那，2750海里
航程要多久？
What's that crossing take?
两天，如果帆一直全开的话
Two days if you're under full sail all the time.
你来的时机真好 没有暴风雨，天气晴朗
Good time of year to be down here. No storms. Nothing.
最近我遇到的风暴够多了
Had enough storms recently.
-好好享受，航程很美丽 -我正有这打算
- Enjoy it. It's a beautiful crossing. - I plan to.
这艘船是谁的？
This boat here. Who does it belong to?
先生？
Senor?
我们接到通报 这艘船从事非法毒品交易
We got a call that this boat was used in some illegal trafficking.
你找错船了 你可以去检查
It's the wrong boat, pal. You can check it if you want to, but, hey...
-你们不能就这样K -这里是巴拿马，朋友
- Hey, you can't just go to... - Hey, this is Panama, friend.
熟悉一下我们的法律好吗？
Get acquainted with the law, huh?
-我K -可卡因
- L... - Coca.
我真的认为你需要 好好熟悉一下我们的法律
Yes, I definitely think you need to get acquainted with it.
过来
Chico.
我K
Well, I...
-你认为他被逮捕了吗？ -那艘船很显眼
- You think they got him? - It's a pretty singular boat.
带这么多可卡因很危险 如果是你在驾船K
That's a lot of coke to be carrying around. If you were at the helm...
我就会被重罚 最少十年跑不掉
I'd be doing some serious time. Ten years, minimum.
没错，我们失去船了
Yeah, you would. We lost the boat.
至少还有死人的钱
At least we got dead man's money.
这是通往我们余生的门票
It's our ticket to the rest of our lives...
扣掉我要寄给 威莫兰女儿的钱
...minus what I'm sending Westmoreland's daughter.
你好
Hey.
-你来了 -我们说好的
- You showed up. - We had a deal.
-这是我哥哥 -你好
- That's my brother. - Hey.
在这里
This way.
我们离开这里，永不回头
So we get out of here and we never look back.
永不回头
We never look back.
迈克，这一切我要谢谢你
I wanna thank you, Michael, for everything.
不客气
You're welcome.
你给我的钱 我只能弄到这东西
It's the best I could do with the money you gave me.
这就可以了
That'll work.
-她很漂亮 -能载我们到想去的地方吧？
- She's very pretty. - She'll get us where we need to go, right?
我不是指船，先生
Not the boat, senor.
我收到你的留言了
So I got your message.
感谢老天让我找到你们
Thank God I found you guys.
的确要感谢老天
Thank God is right.
迈克，林克自由了
Michael, Lincoln's free.
什么？
What?
新闻都在报导 保罗凯勒曼出面作证
It's all over the news. Paul Kellerman came forward.
他交出所有证明文件 而且供出一切
And he had everything documented and he made a full confession.
-你说真的？ -对
- Are you serious? - Yeah.
-一切？ -一切，所有的罪名
- Everything? - Everything. All charges.
真是K
What a...
天啊，真是K 不用再K
Man, what a... No more...
代表你不用再逃亡了
It means you don't have to run anymore.
迈克呢？
What about Michael?
我父亲的朋友正在调查
A friend of my father's is getting into it...
但他有把握 依现在的情况来看
...but he's pretty confident that under the circumstances...
没有人会追究你的罪行
...nobody's gonna pursue you on this.
我得喝一杯
I need a drink.
我去看看有没有饮料
I'll go see what I can find.
来
Here.
帮我解开
Help me out of this.
我们成功了，林克
We did it, Linc.
-我们成功了 -对
- We did it. - Yeah.
不
No.
你们差一点就成功了
You almost did it.
你要钱是吗？
You want the money?
把钱拿走，拿去
Take the money. Take it.
你以为我要的是钱？
You think this is about the money?
五百万这种零用钱？
Pocket change? Like 5 million?
不然你想怎样？ 我哥已经被赦免无罪了
Then what is it about? My brother's been exonerated.
总统已经下台 我们不再是威胁，一切都结束了
The president stepped down. We're not a threat anymore. It's over.
你们也许和我们了结了 但我们还没结束呢
You may be done with us, but that doesn't mean we're done with you.
-警察正在路上 -一切是我引起的
- The police are on their way. - This started with me.
-放过我弟弟 -真是温馨K
- Let my brother go. - Oh, that's sweet, that's sweet.
现代家人之间 已经很少有这种忠诚了
You don't hear that much anymore, that sort of fidelity in families.
两兄弟肯为彼此付出一切
Two brothers who will go to the ends of the earth for each other.
可惜只有一个人能活命
Too bad only one of you will survive.
不
No!
我们快离开
We gotta go.
如果你们不出来投降 我们就会开枪
My men have orders to fire if you don't come out the there with your hands first.
巴拿马领土上发生谋杀案 我们是不会宽容以待的
Murder is not something that we take lightly here on Panamanian soil.
出来就不会再出人命
So come on out of there and there will be no more deaths.
迈克，我杀了人
Michael, I took a man's life.
现在别去想这件事
Don't think about that now.
你和我还有约会，记得吗？
You and I have got a date, remember?
两杯莱姆汁和啤酒，别忘了
Two limes and a couple of beers. Don't forget that.
这是最后的警告
This is your last warning.
把枪给我
Give me the gun.
我杀死一个人
I took a man's life.
我们一起走出去 告诉他们事发过程
We're gonna walk out of here together and we'll tell them exactly what happened.
看着我K
No, look at me, look at me, look at me.
我们告诉他们事发经过
Now, we're gonna tell them what happened.
-好 -我们把一切解释清楚
- Okay. - We're gonna explain everything.
我会尽全力帮你
And I'm gonna do whatever I can to help you.
-好吗？ -好
- Okay? - Yeah.
把枪给我
Now, give me the gun.
拿去
Here.
准备好了吗？
You ready?
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你，莎拉
I love you too, sara.
-好 -准备好了吗？
- Okay. - You ready?
-好了 -好
- Yeah. - All right.
-好 -走吧
- Yeah. - Come on.
不准动
Don't move!
我会开枪的
I'll shoot!
-迈克，你在干嘛？ -所有人不准动
- Michael, what are you doing? - Nobody moves! Nobody!
-你已经为我牺牲过一次 -不
- You sacrificed everything for me once. - No.
-不，不准动 -不，我不能让你这么做
- No! Don't move! - No, I won't let you do this.
迈克K
Michael. Michael!
我该报答你了 是我干的K
Now it's time to say thank you. It was me! It was me!
-是我杀的 -他没有做错事
- I did it! - He's done nothing wrong!
-他是清白的 -是我，人是我杀的
- He's innocent! - I did it! It was me.
-是我杀的 -他没有犯法
- I did it! It was me. - He's done nothing wrong.
他没有杀任何人 他没伤害任何人，迈克
He hasn't shot anybody, he hasn't hurt anybody. Michael.
迈克，告诉他们真相
Michael, tell them the truth!
迈克，他没有犯法
Michael! He's done nothing wrong!
喂？
Hello?
是我
Hey, it's me.
这么着急啊 让我想起我们大学的时候
Oh, getting impatient. Reminds me of when we were in college.
你买机票了吗？
Did you buy the tickets yet?
没有，我还在找
No, I'm still looking,
别买了
Don't.
-什么？ -忘了这件事
- What? - Forget about them.
忘记我的存在
Forget I ever existed.
-不好意思，你会说英文吗？ -会，有事吗？
- Excuse me. You speak English? - Yes. Can I help you?
我要找一名女子 莎拉丹奎迪
Yeah. I'm looking for a woman. Sara Tancredi.
她被带回局里录口供 之后就被释放，她刚离开
She was brought in to give her statement, and then released. You just missed her.
莎拉
Sara!
太好了
Oh, God.
我以为你不来了
I thought you'd never show up.
好，我何时能出狱？
Okay, when am I getting out of here?
我就是来说这件事 出了点小状况
That's the thing. There's been a hiccup.
小状况？
A hiccup?
你们逮到我了
Look, you guys got me.
你们在墨西哥逮到我 算你们厉害，好吗？
You got me fair and square in Mexico, all right?
你们的话我都照做了 你们该依照条件放了我
I did what you wanted me to do. Now, it's time to cut me loose like we agreed.
被逮到不在条件范围内
Getting caught wasn't part of the agreement.
我帮你们设下陷阱时被逮到
I got caught running your setup.
我是你们的诱饵
Being your bait.
我把斯科菲尔德引来 成功达到你们的目的
Now, I got you scofield down here. I got you what you wanted.
你被逮到了，包威
You got caught, Bagwell.
等等，你要去哪里？
Wait. Where you going?!
你要去哪？
Where you going?
我帮你们完成目标 我把他们引来
I got you what you wanted! I got them boys down here!
你们的话我都照做了
I did what you told me to do!
你有听到吗？ 你们的话我都照做了
Do you hear me? I did what you told me to do!
我照你们的话做了
I did what you told me!
我们只能带到这里
This is as far as we go.
（索拿监狱）
（纽约州，长岛 巴索岛研究机构）
将军
General.
这里谈话应该安全吧？
I trust this is a safe place to speak.
有斯科菲尔德的消息
It's scofield.
他被逮捕了
They got him.
（注意，非请勿入）
斯科菲尔德又回到监狱里
Scofield back in the pen.
老实说 我没想到真的会成功
Gotta be honest, I didn't think we'd see it happen.
你很清楚他一定会越狱
You know he's gonna break out.
这是他的天性
It's in his blood.
这正是我们关他的目的
That's exactly what we want him to do.